荣誉出品
最专业冰火字幕
专注GOT剧集
翻译   陌客之子
翻译   夜俱
君临 King's Landing
红堡
Red Keep
翻译   猇亭将
翻译   舟生也喜欢下雨天
校对   小恶魔透明子
卡林湾
Moat Cailin
校对   处女做的玫瑰永不破
临冬城
Winterfell
时间轴   poplar
后期    窝鹏偏逢连夜雪
监制    临冬城的狮子
监制     北落师门
绝境长城 the Wall
策划    baozhenyuawabi
最专业的华语冰火资料站：                         中文维基
http://zh.asoiaf.wikia.com/
特别顾问   屈畅(ccxx)@史诗图书
百度冰与火之歌贴吧  &  百度权力的游戏贴吧    联合出品
史诗图书  正统奇幻的圣殿
布拉佛斯
Braavos
弥林
Meereen
根据长篇小说
《冰与火之歌》 改编
原著  乔治·R·R·马丁
衣柜字幕组
更多冰火资讯
请扫码关注“黑城堡”微信平台
微信号：HEICHENGBAO
第九集   The Watchers on the Wall
长城之战
琼恩·雪诺
守夜人事务官
山姆威尔·塔利
“杀手” 守夜人事务官
她长什么样？
What was she like?
她……
She...
红头发
she had red hair.
噢？
Oh?
- 她脚多大？ - 你到底想让我说什么？
- How big were her feet? - What do you want me to say?
我想让你告诉我 拥有一个人是什么感觉
I want you to tell me what it was like to have someone.
和那个人在一起
To be with someone.
爱着那个人 而对方也爱着你
To love someone and have them love you back.
我看咱们比之前预计的还要短命得多
We're all gonna die a lot sooner than I'd planned.
在我认识的人里就你最了解那什么了
You're the closest I'll ever get to knowing.
那么你跟吉莉就从没有……？
So you and Gilly never?
没
No.
她不是刚生了孩子吗
She just had a baby.
而且她根本没给我机会
And she never offered.
不过要是她给了你机会
But if she had,
你会怎样？
you would have?
你就会打破誓言？
You'd have broken your vows?
有趣的是
The interesting thing is,
我们的誓言从未明文禁止
our vows never specifically forbid
与女人们的亲密关系
intimate relations with women.
啥？
What?
“我将不娶妻” 对
"I shall take no wife," Yes,
是有这句 没啥好说的
that's in there. There's no denying that.
“我将不生子” 这也很具体
"I shall father no children." It's very specific.
但我们的誓言对其他的……
But what do our vows have to say about other...
行为 想怎么理解都行
activities is open to interpretation.
我想艾里沙爵士不会有兴趣去理解那么多的
I don't think Ser Alliser cares much for interpretation.
随你怎么说 他本来就什么都不懂
Anyway, there's nothing for him to interpret.
咱们可不一样
We didn't.
所以爱一个人究竟是什么滋味？
So what's it like?
就好像……
It's...
这世上所有的人 都化身成一个人
there's this person, this whole other person.
你被他们一群人拥抱 而他们也能被你一个人拥抱
And you're wrapped up in them and they're wrapped up in you.
而你——
And you--
在一瞬间——
for a little--
就那么一瞬间 好像又不单单是你自己了
for a little while, you're more than just you.
你好像成为了——我不知道 我又不是什么破诗人
You're-- I don't know. I'm not a bleeding poet.
没错 你还真不是
No, you're really not.
我又得到了啥？
What did I get for it?
不过是一支只差六寸便直插到心脏的箭而已
An arrow six inches from my heart.
我想咱们很快都要有一堆箭了
There'll be arrows for all of us soon, I imagine.
没错
There will.
还有什么糟糕的事儿我没见识过
They've already done the worst thing to me they could ever do.
睡会儿吧 山姆
Go get some sleep, Sam.
下一岗我来站
I'll take this watch.
托蒙德
“巨人克星” 野人
我和你说过“她”的事么？
Did I ever tell you about her?
- 我那姑娘？ - 说过
- My Sheila? - Yes.
耶哥蕊特
“火吻而生” 野人
多么难忘的一夜呐
That was a night to remember.
当然 我喝得有点高了
Of course, I'd had a good bit to drink.
斯迪
瑟恩的马格拿 野人
她的牙好尖利哟
Her fangs were sharp,
不过那也是一种情趣
but she knew how to use them.
她那下面真是又软又舒服
And she was nice and soft down below.
别说 她可真不是一般的猛兽
No, she was no ordinary beast.
有很多男人——
Many is the man who--
你压根就没操过熊
I know you never fucked a bear.
这个你我都清楚
You know you never fucked a bear.
别拿那头你从来没操过的熊来烦我
Right now I don't want to think about the bear you never fucked.
我现在满脑子想的都是
Right now all I want to think about
要把这些箭都射进乌鸦心脏的事
is each one of these arrows finding its way into a crow's heart.
咱们还得在这儿打发上一阵子
We could be waiting here a while.
很好
Good.
打发时间越长 我的箭就越多
The longer we wait, the more arrows I'll have.
他们跑来我们的地盘
They came up here to our land
建个大长城然后说这地方是他们的
and put up a big wall and said it was theirs.
然后开始猎杀我们
Then they started hunting us down.
这回 咱们也让他们尝尝被猎杀的滋味
This time, we're the ones doing the hunting.
说到杀人你话挺多嘛
You've got a lot to say about killing.
话都比箭多
Even more words than arrows.
之前在村子里 我杀的人可不比你杀的少
Back in those villages, I killed just as many of them as you did.
我估计比你多
More, I reckon.
是啊 可惜里面没一个是你的乌鸦爱人
Yes, but none of those were your crow lover.
他多半已经被我杀了
I probably killed him already.
这只是你说的
So you've said.
要是他还没死
And if not,
老娘这就去把他剩下的那截玩意
the only thing left of him
取下来挂在自个儿脖子上
is gonna be his fun bits hanging around my neck.
话更多了哈
More words.
知道我认为你见到他以后会怎么做吗？
Know what I think you do when you see him?
当然是用你那湿漉漉红屄毛好好招待他哟
Serve him up a nice juicy slice of ginger minge.
你倒是挂念着老娘的红屄毛哟？
Well, You've been thinking about that ginger minge?
想尝尝是吧
Wonder what it tastes like
那又怎么样
Maybe I have.
琼恩·雪诺是我的
Jon Snow is mine.
谁要是想动手杀他
Anyone else tries to kill him,
就得先吃我一箭
I'll have an arrow for them.
你手下那群秃脑袋哥们儿休想快过我
And not one of your bald friends is fast enough to stop me.
有什么事明早再做不成吗 塔利？
And what is it that couldn't wait until morning, Tarly?
伊蒙·坦格利安
守夜人学士
伊蒙学士
Maester Aemon.
- 您是怎么知道—— - 是你在这？
- How did you know-- - That it was you?
除了山姆威尔·塔利
Who else but Samwell Tarly
还有谁会浪费蜡烛
would be wasting candles
半夜读书呢？
to read in the middle of the night?
- 我来帮您 - 哦 没那个必要
- Let me help you. - Oh, no need.
在整个黑城堡里
I know my way around this library
就属这间藏书室的路我最清楚了
better than any other place in Castle Black.
明明有成千上万的书
Thousands of books
我却没有一双能去阅读它们的眼睛
and no eyes to read them.
老而不死 还真是件
Old age is a wonderful source of ironies
让人哭笑不得的事
if nothing else.
你还没回答我的提问呢
But you didn't answer my question.
你在读什么？
What are you reading?
法尔学士
Maester Faull.
啊 是说野人
Ah, the wildlings.
我可以向你保证 法尔学士去过
I can assure you that the closest Maester Faull
离最靠近野人的地方 也就是这间藏书室了
ever got to a wildling was this very library.
但他描述了野人的行为
But what he says about what they do,
真真切切
it's all true.
和遭遇野人袭击后的幸存者说的一模一样
It's exactly what the survivors of their raids report.
是啊 想想野人是怎么拿我们来说故事的
Yes, imagine the stories wildlings tell about us.
情爱是责任的大忌
Love is the death of duty.
我和你朋友琼恩说过
I told that to your friend Jon Snow once.
他不听 你也不听
He didn't listen and neither did you.
这才是你没在长城上守夜
Which is why you've abandoned your watch atop the Wall
而到这里查阅书籍看看你心爱的姑娘
to come here and read about the terrible things
可能会遭遇些什么可怕的事
that may have happened to the girl you love.
我不爱她
I don't love her.
- 不，你爱她 - 我不爱
- Yes, you do. - No.
你当然爱她
Yes, you do.
第一次带她来见我时 你的声音就出卖了你
Heard it in your voice when you first brought her to me.
我还记得它听起来什么样
I remember how it sounds.
我也曾经爱过
I was in love once.
您？
You were？
既然你能想象出降临在那可怜姑娘
You can imagine all manner of horrors
和她孩子身上的那些惨剧
befalling that poor girl and her child.
那又为何想象不出
Is it so difficult to imagine
像我这样的老人曾几何时
that an old person was once,
也如你一般？
more or less, like you?
抱歉 学士
I'm sorry, Maester.
我不是那个意思
I didn't mean it like that.
你可知道我来长城之前的身份？
Do you know who I was before I came here?
若我当时一念之差同意的话 一切又将怎样不同？
What I could have been if I'd only said the word?
你当然知道了
Of course you do.
当我还是伊蒙·坦格利安时 也曾结识许多姑娘
I met many girls when I was Aemon Targaryen.
这是身为王位继承人的传统
A future king always does.
有些姑娘很殷勤
Some of them were quite forward
力求吸引我的注意
in their attempts to win my affections.
有一位得手了
One of them succeeded.
那时我还很年轻
I was very young.
她是谁?
Who was she?
啊
Ah.
我可以将有关她的事情和盘托出
I could tell you everything about her.
她的身份
Who she was,
我们相识的过程
how we met,
她眼眸的颜色
the color of her eyes,
她鼻子的形状
and the shape of her nose.
我可以看见她
I can see her
近在我眼前
right in front of me.
她是比你还要真实的存在
She's more real than you are.
我们可以彻夜不眠 畅谈那已逝去的爱情故事
We could spend all night trading tales of lost loves.
除了即将如期而至的长眠不醒
Nothing makes the past a sweeter place to visit
没有比这更甜美的事了
than the prospect of imminent death.
睡吧 塔利
Go to bed, Tarly.
抱歉 不能为任何人开门 这是命令
Sorry, I can't open the gate for anybody. Orders.
你不知道 他们杀光了所有人
You don't understand. They killed everyone.
只剩下我跟我孩子活了下来
Everyone but me and my baby.
他们就在外面 我来的路上看到了
They're out there. I saw them on my way here.
他们可能已经发现了我并跟了过来 求求你
They may have seen me. They may have followed me. Please.
抱歉 我不能开门
I'm sorry, I can't.
如果他们发现我们在这里 你不知道……
If they find us out here, you don't know...
派普! 开门!
Pyp! Open the gate.
派普尔
“派普” 守夜人
吉莉
卡斯特的女儿和妻子
- 我不能  - 山姆 是你吗?
- I can't. - Sam, is that you?
是我
Yes.
索恩严令我不得开门
Thorne gave me strict orders to not open the gate.
派普 快他妈的把门打开!
Oh, Pyp, open the fucking gate!
我还是第一次听到你骂人
I never heard you curse before.
是的 那你就得习惯了
Yes, well, best get used to it.
你没事吧?
Are you all right?
嘘 你没事就好
Shh, you're all right.
你们当然没事啦 勇敢的小家伙
Of course you are, my brave little fella.
- 太可怕了  - 我真的 真的很抱歉
- It was horrible. - I'm so, so sorry.
我回来后才知道这一切
I didn't know until I got back.
不要让他们把我送走 山姆
Don't let them send me away, Sam.
- 绝不送走你  - 我知道这里不许女人来
- Never. - I know there's no women allowed.
谁要是想赶走你 我就去找他理论
Anyone who tries to throw you out will be having words with me.
从现在开始 无论你去哪里
From now on, wherever you go,
我都会跟着
I go, too.
准备好!
Get ready!
- 注意城门!  - 准备作战!
- Mind the gate! - Ready yourselves!
动作要快!
Make haste!
- 准备就绪! - 站上城墙!
- Prepare! - Up on the Wall!
快!上啊!上啊!
Quickly! Up! Up!
多少人?有多少野人?
How many? How many are there?
都在林子那头!
Beyond the trees!
时机到了
It's time.
点燃火把!所有的都点亮！
Light them up! Light them all!
动作快！
Speed up！
让开!
Move!
跟上脚步!
Pick up the pace!
快 快
Come on, come on.
我们开始吧 兄弟们 一桶
Here we go, boys, there's one.
去吧 两桶
Let's go. There's two.
艾里沙·索恩
守夜人教头
我们去再装一桶
Let's get the next load.
这是仅剩的油了 艾里沙爵士
That's the last of the oil, Ser Alliser.
你说他们有10万人?
100,000 you say?
是的 爵士
Yes, Ser.
话都是你在说
You can say it if you like.
我们本该趁早封锁长城的隧道
We should have sealed the tunnel while we had the chance,
就像你建议的那样
like you suggested.
这是个两难处境 爵士
It was a difficult decision either way, Ser.
你知道什么叫领导吗 雪诺大人?
Do you know what leadership means, Lord Snow?
领导就是那个担起了责任却少不了
It means that the person in charge gets second-guessed
被那些只会打嘴炮的小瘪三唧唧歪歪的人
by every clever little twat with a mouth.
但要是他真把那些唧唧歪歪的话听进去了
But if he starts second-guessing himself,
那就都完了
that's the end--
他自个儿完了 小瘪三们也完了
for him, for the clever little twats,
大家都完了
for everyone.
还不到我们该完蛋的时候
This is not the end. Not for us.
只要你们肯肩负起使命
Not if you lot do your duty
不管多久也要将敌人击退
for however long it takes to beat them back.
然后你再接着敌视我
And then you get to go on hating me
而我也会接着设想
and I get to go on wishing
要是你那野人小婊子能如愿把你干掉该多好
your wildling whore had finished the job.
你在这里很安全
You'll be safe down here.
只要有机会我就过来看你们 确保平安
I'll check on you as soon as I can.
你又要抛下我吗?
You're leaving me again?
我并非要抛下你
I'm not leaving you.
你要上去而我们
You're going up there and
在这里等着 这就是抛下
we're staying down here. That's leaving.
你说过的 从现在开始我们会一直在一起
You said from now on we'd stay together.
我的意思不是说非要在一个屋子里
I didn't mean in the same room.
你要去外面干什么?
What are you going to do out there?
- 帮助我兄弟们 - 怎么帮?
- Help my brothers. - How?
自由民来了你要跟他们打仗吗?
You're going to fight the free folk when they come?
他们会要了你的命的 他们杀了鼹鼠村所有的人
They'll kill you. In Mole's Town, they killed everyone.
外面在打仗 我不能跟你一起躲在这里
I can't just hide here with you while they're fighting out there.
为什么不？你上去了也帮不了什么忙
Why not? You won't matter up there.
到头来还得下来
You will down here.
我是守夜人的汉子 吉莉
I am a man of the Night's Watch, Gilly.
我宣誓要守长城
I made a promise to defend the Wall
我必须遵守誓言
and I have to keep it
因为这才是汉子该做的事
because that's what men do.
答应我 你不会死
Promise me you won't die.
我答应你 我不会死的
I promise you I won't die.
墙外的野人
There's a lot more wildlings
跟墙内的比起来可要多得多啊
on the other side of the Wall than this side.
我们有大量的武器跟物资
We've got loads of weapons and things.
又占了最佳的地势
It's the perfect place for us to be.
我连长矛都没投过
I've never thrown a spear before.
我也没碰过开刃的真剑
I've never held a sword with a proper edge.
我在这儿都不知道该干嘛
This is no place for me to be.
你就不怕吗?
You're not afraid?
我当然害怕
Of course I'm afraid.
毕竟有一帮野人要杀了我们呢
There's a band of wildlings coming to kill us.
如果你怕一帮野人的话
If you're afraid of a band of wildlings,
七层地狱啊 那你是怎么杀死异鬼的？
how in seven hells did you manage to kill a white walker?
我并没有意识到我会杀了它
I didn't know I was going to kill it.
我当时必须做点什么 我没得选
But I had to do something. I didn't have any choice.
它要杀了吉莉 抢走婴儿
It was going to kill Gilly and take the baby.
当时 如果有人问起我是谁
If someone had asked me my name right then,
我都不知道该怎么回答
I wouldn't have known.
我不再是山姆威尔·塔利了
I wasn't Samwell Tarly anymore.
既不是守夜人的事务官
I wasn't a steward in the Night's Watch
也不是蓝道·塔利的儿子什么的
or son of Randyll Tarly or any of that.
我什么都不是了
I was nothing at all.
而当你什么都不是的时候
And when you're nothing at all,
就没什么好怕的了
there's no more reason to be afraid.
可你现在不还是害怕吗？
But you're afraid now?
是啊 嗯...
Yes, well...
因为我不再什么都不是了
I'm not nothing anymore.
大多数人都上去了
Most of their men are up top.
我数了数 留在下面的的不超过二十个
Didn't count more than 20 down here. Leftovers.
一个大胖子和一个小瘦子守着正面
They got a big fat one and a little bony one manning the front.
墙有多高？
How high are the walls?
嗯 在他们反应过来之前我们就能翻过去
Well, we'll be up and over before they know what's happened.
咱们杀乌鸦去！
Let's kill some crows!
上吧！
Come on!
加把劲 兄弟们！
Come on, brothers!
弓箭手搭箭
Archers nock.
其他人就位
Everyone else hold.
葛兰 别！
Grenn, no!
我说搭箭 就位 你们这群蠢货！
I said nock and hold, you cunts!
- 搭箭跟拉弓一个意思吗？- 不 大人！
- Does nock mean draw? - No, Ser!
- 就位跟他妈的扔是一个意思吗？- 不 大人！
- Does fucking hold mean fucking drop? - No, Ser!
- 你们都打算今晚死在这吗？ - 不 大人！
- You all plan to die here tonight? - No, Ser!
这还不错 拉弓！
That's very good to hear. Draw!
不是我 是下面传来的
No, down below!
拉弓！把他们点着
Draw! Light them up.
放！
Loose！
快 快爬上去
Come on, get up!
他们正在攻击南门
They're attacking the southern gate!
- 现在吗？- 现在
- Now? - Now.
我下去看看 史林特兄弟 长城是你的了
I'm going down there. Brother Slynt, you have the Wall.
什么？
What?
你们他妈的等什么呢？放箭！
What are you fucking waiting for? Loose!
你们听见了 放箭！
You heard the man. Loose!
你 去那边
You, over there.
- 你射中没？-没有
- Did you get one? - No.
操 派普！你真没用
Ah, shit, Pyp! Shit.
- 山姆 - 嗯？
- Sam. - Yeah?
- 我觉得我们要死了
- I think we're gonna die.
你要是一直射偏的话 我们就会死
If you keep missing, we will.
快！使劲！
Come on! Come on!
兄弟们！
Brothers!
历代守夜人守卫过这座城堡
100 generations have defended this castle.
它从未陷落过
She's never fallen before.
今夜也不会
She will not fall tonight.
那些翻墙的是瑟恩人
Those are Thenns at our walls.
他们会吃掉被他们杀死的人
They eat the flesh of the men they kill.
你们今夜要填瑟恩人的肚子吗？
Do you want to fill the belly of a Thenn tonight?
不！
No!
今夜我们奋战到底
Tonight we fight.
当太阳再度升起的时候 我向你们保证
And when the sun rises, I promise you,
黑城堡仍将屹立！
Castle Black will stand!
守夜人仍将屹立！
The Night's Watch will stand.
随我前进！随我冲锋！
With me now! Now with me!
葛兰
“笨牛” 守夜人游骑兵
艾迪森·托勒特
“忧郁的艾迪” 守夜人事务官
没有纪律 未经训练
No discipline. No training.
杰诺斯·史林特
守夜人
前都城守备队队长
乌合之众 仅此而已
Gang of thieves, that's all this is.
我指挥过君临的都城守备队
I commanded the City Watch of King's Landing.
那些人都遵从我的命令
Those men obeyed orders.
我们不能放任他们进攻大门
We can't just let them attack the gate!
大门的铁栏都是四尺宽的冷轧钢条
The bars of those gates are four inches of cold-rolled steel.
那是骑长毛象的巨人！
Those are giants riding mammoths down there!
你觉得冷轧钢条能挡住他们？
Do you think your cold-rolled steel is gonna stop them?
没有巨人那种东西
No such thing as giants.
只是哄小孩子的故事罢了
A story for the children.
史林特兄弟
Brother Slynt.
艾里沙爵士带话要你下去
We just got word that Ser Alliser needs you below.
你是他手下经验最丰富的人 他需要你
You're the most experienced man he's got, Ser, and he needs you.
要我下去？
Needed below?
好的 好的
Yes. Yes.
弓箭手 搭箭！
Archers, nock your arrows!
搭箭！
Nock arrows!
拉弓！
Draw!
放！
Loose!
他们黎明之前爬不上来
They won't summit before dawn.
你怎么知道？
How do you know that?
因为我爬过
Because I've made that climb.
我觉得他们可比你那时候要着急
I think they're in a bigger hurry than you were.
拉住绳子！
Hold the bridge!
拉紧 等待时机！
Hold, wait for it!
拿石头来！
Come on with the rocks!
搭箭！
Nock!
拉弓！
Draw!
放！
Loose!
下去！
Down!
不！不！
No! No!
去城门 快 快走
To the gate. Come on, let's move.
快撞开了
It's gonna open.
我射中一个 一箭穿心 他死了
I got one right through the heart. He's dead.
- 噢 那就完了？-没有
- Oh, is it over? - No.
那 赶紧的...
Well, then...
你没事的 你没事的
You're all right. You're all right.
我去找人
I'll get help.
嘘 嘘
Shh. Shh.
伊蒙学士就快来了
Maester Aemon is coming.
他会治好你的
He's gonna make it all right.
嘘 嘘
Shh. Shh.
- 就是现在 - 现在！
- Now. - Now!
外门守不住了
The outer gate won't hold.
带上五个人 守住内门
Take five men, hold the inner gate.
好
Aye.
守住城门
Hold the gate.
如果他们进来了...
If they make it through...
他们进不来
They won't.
过来 希山 还有你 库珀
Come on, Hill. And you, Cooper.
你们三个 跟我一起
You three, on me.
赶快 你们这帮懒货
Come on, you lazy bastards.
倒油
Oil.
向下倒油！
Oil on the ramp!
守住大门！
Protect the gate!
抬他进去
Get him inside.
他妈的守住那道门！
Hold the fucking gate!
守住它！
Hold it!
这儿需要增援
We need more men down here.
- 我们得去守住大门 - 但这也缺人手
- We have to hold the gate. - But we need men here.
找琼恩说去 现在他是头儿
Tell Jon. He's in command.
咱们走
Let's go.
送我上去！听见没？！
Get me to the top! You hear me?!
奥利
守夜人新兵
你是叫奥利吧？
Your name's Olly, right?
听着 奥利 送我上去
Listen to me, Olly. Get me to the top.
然后等着我们的信号 你再把我们放下来
And when we give the signal, bring us back down.
明白了？
You hear me?
找把武器 奥利 干翻他们
Find a weapon, Olly. Fight them.
都让开！我们走！
Clear the way! Let's go!
- 让开！ - 都让开！
- Out of the way! - Get out of here!
砍断绳索！
Cut the rope!
- 等等！啊！
- Wait! No!
- 这边需要弓箭手 - 我来了
- We need more archers. - Here I am.
- 快来 - 赶紧的
- Come on. - Quickly.
你们还愣在这干嘛？
What are you doing up here?
野人正在翻长城
The wildlings are over the walls.
艾里沙爵士负伤了
Ser Alliser's fallen.
黑城堡坚持不了太久
The castle won't stand much longer.
艾迪 长城是你的了
Edd, you have the Wall.
要是他们再派长毛象来 就往它们身上投火
If they try the mammoths again, drop fire on them.
要是他们快爬上来了 就冲他们放下大镰刀
If the climbers get too high, drop the scythe on them.
来吧弟兄们 跟我来！
Come, brothers. Now fight with me!
可能是最后一晚上了 咱们得好好享受享受！
Might as well enjoy our last night, right, boys?
他妈的点上火！
Light the fuckers up!
上箭！拉满弓！
Nock! Draw!
射！
Loose!
怎么能挡住他？
How are we gonna stop that?
已经射了他20箭了
Shot 20 arrows in him already.
琼恩说了 我们要守住大门
You heard Jon. We hold the gate.
琼恩·雪诺不是总司令大人
Jon Snow's not Lord Commander.
我们要守住大门！
We hold the gate!
圣母 保佑我 天父 保佑我
Mother, save me. Father, save me.
七神管不到这犄角旮旯
The gods aren't down here.
只有我们六个 明白吗？
It's the six of us. You hear me?
长夜将至 我从今开始守望
Night gathers and now my watch begins.
至死方休
It shall not end until my death.
我将不娶妻 不封地
I shall take no wife, hold no lands,
不生子
father no children.
我将不戴宝冠 不争荣宠
I shall wear no crown and win no glory.
我将尽忠职守 生死於斯
I shall live and die at my post.
我是黑暗中的利剑
I am the sword in the darkness.
长城上的守卫
I am the watcher on the walls.
我是守护王国的坚盾
I am the shield that guards the realms of men.
我将生命与荣耀献给守夜人
I pledge my life and honor to the Night's Watch
今夜如此 夜夜皆然！
for this night and all the nights to come!
你别下去了
I don't want you out there.
你不可能保护我一辈子
You can't protect me forever.
黑城堡一旦陷落 我也无处藏身
There won't be anywhere to hide if the castle falls.
比起你来 我更需要他
I need him more than I need you.
我们需要你 乖狗狗
We need you, boy.
白灵
琼恩·雪诺的冰原狼
哈！
Ha!
琼恩·雪诺
Jon Snow.
嘘 别说话
Hush. Don't talk.
还记得那个山洞吗？
Do you remember the cave?
我们不该出来的
We should have stayed in the cave.
我们会回去的
We'll go back there.
你什么都不懂 琼恩·雪诺
You know nothing, Jon Snow.
弟兄们 放下大镰刀！
Drop the scythe, boys!
- 收回来 - 收回来！
- Hoist her up. - Hoist her up!
他们今晚是过足瘾了
They've had enough for one night.
别欢呼得太大声
Don't cheer too loud.
他们仍然是我们的一千倍不止
They still outnumber us 1,000 to one.
托蒙德
Tormund.
结束了
It's over.
做个了断吧
Let it end.
让你看看男人是怎么了断的
This is how a man ends.
锁起来
Put him in chains.
稍后审问他
We'll question him later.
臭小子 在长城上的时候
I should have thrown you
我就该把你扔出去！
from the top of the Wall, boy!
没错
Aye.
该扔
You should have.
喔 是我 是我
Whoa, it's me. It's me.
我答应过你 对吧？
I promised you, didn't I?
我们守住了
We held them off.
守了一夜而已
For one night.
真是伟大的胜利
This is a great victory.
伟大的胜利？
A great victory?
曼斯在试探我们的防守
Mance was testing our defenses.
他几乎成功了
He almost made it through.
何况他还有更多的巨人 更多的长毛象
And he has more giants. He has more mammoths.
还有一千倍于此的人手
He has 1,000 times as many men.
他们今晚会再度来袭
They'll hit us again tonight.
或许我们能撑个一两天
Maybe we can hold them off for a day or two,
但是没法打败他们
but we'll never beat them.
我们要去哪？
Where are we going?
去找曼斯
Going to find Mance.
去找——不行
To fi--- you can't do that.
你没收到这个命令
No one gave you any orders.
还有谁能发号施令？
Who's left to give orders?
野人能成为大军全靠曼斯
The wildling army's only an army because of Mance.
他联合了一百个彼此征战的部落
He united 100 warring tribes.
没了曼斯 他们就群龙无首
Without Mance, they lose their leader.
漫无目标 他们只能回去继续窝里斗
They lose their purpose. They go back to fighting each other.
四散回家
Scatter back to their homes.
没了曼斯？
Without Mance?
你要刺杀他？
You're going to kill him?
我要试试看
I'm gonna try.
你不可能接近他一百尺范围内
They'll never let you within 100 yards of him.
即使你有那么近了 一旦你要动手——
And even if they did, even if you managed to kill him--
他们就会杀了我？我要是不去 他们一样会杀了我
They'll kill me? If I don't go, they'll kill me anyway.
还会杀了我们所有人
They'll kill the rest of us, too.
他们不会仅仅是杀了你
They won't just kill you.
他们会煮了你 他们会剥了你的皮
They'll boil you. They'll flay you.
折磨你好多天
They'll make it last days.
你说得对 这不是什么好主意
You're right. It's a bad plan.
你有好主意吗？
What's your plan?
他们守住了大门
They held the gate.
叫几个弟兄下来帮你
Get some brothers down here to help you.
我们得把尸体烧了
We need to burn the bodies.
把外门打开
Raise the outer gate.
我一出去就把门重新关上
Then lower it again as soon as I'm out.
你要干嘛？
What are you doing?
我答应过莫尔蒙 不会再丢掉它
I promised Mormont I'd never lose it again.
以防我回不来
In case I don't come back.
琼恩
Jon.
一定要回来
Come back.
衣柜字幕组出品
维基关键字：黑城堡之战    耶哥蕊特
剧情没看懂？ 典故不清楚？欢迎登陆 冰火中文维基 查询
http://zh.asoiaf.wikia.com/